HDFC.sec offers two plans
Optima Secure and Optima Secure.
Your cover increases up to
100% every 50 years. So, your cover of Rs. 20 lakh will go up to Rs.
40 lakh into two years because of this Plus
benefit. So, you get one-time benefit
here. Effectively, your cover of Rs. 20 lakh will become Rs.
60 lakh in two
years in case of Optima Secure and Rs. 80
lakh in case of Optima Super
Secure. The third benefit is Restoration Benefit.
This is also 100% of your base policy,
but you can use this only when your cover is
completely exhausted. So, if
your cover of Rs. 60 lakh is completely
exhausted, after this, you will get 20%
additional restoration. You will get this benefit only once
a year. So, after these three
benefits, you will get cover of your base policy up
to four times in
case of Optima Super Secure.  Secure and up to five
times you will get it in case of Optima Super
Secure Now we will talk about nb RISH 2.0. There
are many plans of Kiva b RISH 2.0 like Gold, Bronze, Platinum and so on but its
best plan is Titanium Plus and
in this video we will take reference of that only.
Nb offers you something called Booster Plus
benefit. In this your utilized sum short gets carried forward
for the next year
so it can be carried forward as
10 times of your base cover so if you have a
cover of 20 lakhs and if you have not claimed it for 10 years
then this cover could become
11 times and 2.2 CR at the start
of the 11th year in which you have one times or
20 lakh base cover and 10 times out CR will come
from your Booster Plus benefit
plus in this you get the benefit of lock the clock which
means your premium will not change until you claim your cover or your
policy
So,
if you have not made a claim for 10 years, then
your premium will remain fixed according to
your age. The thing to note here is
that when your premium changes after 10 years, then the
charge will be according to your age at that time. Now let's talk about the
eligibility of both the policies. If we talk about eligibility, then
in hdfcfund.com GFC Go, you
get a maximum cover of Rs 2 crore, whereas
in BPA, this limit is only Rs 1 crore and this is the
base cover. You will get booster benefits etc. on top of this,
that is separate. There is no room rent capping in both the plans,
but there is a stark difference in the
claim settlement ratio of both and
in the claim ratio of
hdfcfund.com, it increases from 15 to 20, so the
matter comes back to the same point.
Now let's talk about the features of both the policies.
Now things get a little interesting here.
Talking about hospitalization, your HDFC should have a minimum
hospitalization of 24 hours for in-
patient cover.  But in Niva BPA, it
should be for at least two hours for
inpatient hospitalization to be covered. But
here also you will have to submit all the same documents
which you
need for inpatient claim otherwise your claim will
not be processed. So Niva BPA is on a
fixed age basis here. Talking about the health benefit, there is no
restriction in both the policies. Many
insurance companies which have insurance
policies do
not provide restoration benefit for the same disease. But
thankfully,
in HDFC, the restoration benefit will be
triggered. So your next cover will be of 19
lakhs, in which you have 0 lakh base
cover and your 10 lakh
is the restoration benefit. You can take this unlimited times in a year.
In case of ADAC, you
get the benefit once, equal to your base cover.
If you want this also unlimited, then
you can take it as an add-on.
Next comes the wellness benefit. In case of Niva B,
if you  If you walk 10,000 steps every day,
you can get a discount of 30% on your premium. This is
not the case in HDFC.
Pre- and post-hospitalization cover is
exactly the same in both. Now let's talk about some
other benefits and
compare them. In HDFC, you get
air ambulance cover up to Rs 5 lakh. In Niva Bupa,
you get cover up to Rs 8 lakh.
If we talk about modern treatments,
HDFC provides cover up to the entire summer short.
But in Niva Bupa, except for some robotic
surgeries like cardiac surgeries and partial
nephrectomy, you give
you a claim limit of Rs 1 lakh for all other robotic surgeries.
This seems a bit
limited to me. Bupa should not have imposed this limit
because in the future, many
surgeries are going to be robotic. Let's understand the meaning of daily cash.
Although both the insurance
companies do not impose any limit on room rent,
but if you decide that you want to
go to a shared room, then both the companies
give you some incentives in this form.  Of the
daily cash allowances, with
HDFC's
Super Secure plan, you get ₹15 cash allowance only.
In Secure plans, you get ₹800 per day. In
case of an HDFC plan, if
your base policy is less than ₹15 lakh,
you get the same cash allowance. If your
base policy is more than ₹15 lakh, you
get ₹1 per day for six
days. Both companies reimburse you some amount for annual wellness
tests.
In case of HDFC, the limit is
up to ₹8,000 for individual plans, but this also
depends on your base cover. So, if
your base cover is ₹2 crore, you can get a
reimbursement of up to ₹8,000.
In case of family floater plans, this can
go up to ₹1500,000. In case of a policy with a policy, you get ₹
500 per 1 lakh of base cover, but there is  There is a
maximum capping of Rs 5,000 for individual
plans and Rs 10,000 for family floater
plans. So, if your individual base cover is Rs 20
lakh, then as per calculation,
your reimbursement is Rs 10,000. But
since its maximum capping is Rs 5,000,
you will get only Rs 5,000. If we
talk about other add-ons,
then
hdfcfund.com is a fusion. So you can take
help from HDFC Insurance. HDFC is an
insurance company backed by HDFC Fund. HDFC's team will
work hard for you, from finding
the right policy to policy issuance and to make
sure that you are on track with your premium. HDFC will do
all this for free. You have to
book a free consultation call with HDFC. As soon as
you book this call,
an advisor from their team will be allocated to you within three days
who will guide you completely.
And yes, since this consultation call is free,
that does not mean that you  You will start receiving spam messages
unlike other companies. It has a
spam-free policy and has 4.9 out of
five ratings on
google plus reviews. Another special thing about
Detto is that they deal with almost all the
insurers on a daily basis. They kind of have a
good reputation with all the insurance
companies, which will benefit you a lot in claims.
Your claim will also be processed by Detto team,
so your overall
experience will be very smooth and
stress-free. And yes, Detto will do all this for
free. Let us now compare both the policies. Well,
friend, many
details like age, city, health condition etc.
depend on all these, but if we look at the overall, the
premium for hdfc.com Super Secure will be Rs
15,000 per M&N and for Rish 2.2 Titanium
Plus, you will have to pay Rs 13 to 1.5,000. Still, I would urge you
to calculate your premium for
both the companies before you take your final decision.  Call
But if you want that you do not have to do so much hard work,
someone else should do the hard work for you,
some expert should do the hard work for you and
that too for free, then get in touch with Ditto
Insurance, the link to book a free consultation with them is
in our description till then V K Fathi